Dean Nortje

BISHons Multimedia Student, BSc Information and Knowledge Systems Graduate



Mobile Number

dean.nortje@me.com





Github.com/Deannortje

Linkedin.com/in/Deannortje

deannortje.github.io



EDUCATION

BIS Honours Multimedia.

University of Pretoria, South Africa, Completing in 2022

BSc Information and Knowledge Systems, University of Pretoria,

South Africa, 2021

Senior Certificate/Matric

Bachelor's Pass, Redhill High School, Johannesburg, South Africa, 2016

AWS Training and Certification

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner, 2022



AWARDS

Achieved 2nd place for Cos301 Software engineering project awarded by the EBIT Faculty (2021)

Achieved scrolls at Redhill High School for Science Expo

Achieved scrolls at Redhill High School for Swimming

Played 1st Team Rugby Gr 11-12

Competed in the Inter-High u18 Swimming Gr 12



Information Technology (DRS)

PERSONAL PROFILE



BSc Information and Knowledge Systems and BIS Multimedia Honours graduate from the University of Pretoria, with a passion for software development, eagerness to learn and develop skills.

Experience in multiple programming languages, listed under technical skills.

During studies, completed a software engineering project for Retro Rabbit, a software development company. Formed part of a five-person team that designed an application that offers a digital work environment with a collection of tools that made communications between colleagues as seamless as possible, aiming to replicate an in-person interaction.

Link to project: https://github.com/COS301-SE-2021/Rabbitania

One honours project focused on utilising AWS tools and services. This group project was completed over a period of 3 months for a software development company called Gendac. An application was created to upload, analyse, categorise, store and search for CV documents. Link to project: https://github.com/Deannortje/imy-772-gendac-project

The above-mentioned projects were completed using an agile environment, Github, databases, APIs, Amazon Webservices and multiple programming languages.

All projects involving application design or user interaction required the use of UI/UX design using adobe XD and Figma.

EXPERIENCE



Construction Jnr Foreman (Student employment opportunity)

Advanced Interiors and Construction, Johannesburg, South Africa, Dec 2020 – Jan 2021

Role: Management of construction tasks and supervision of staff

- Managed an array of construction tasks
- Organised and delegated tasks
- Ensured use of personal protection equipment standards

DevSecOps Intern (Student employment opportunity)

DRS, Johannesburg, South Africa, Jan 2021 - Mar 2021

Role: Intern

- Researched and learnt about development pipelines in a security context
- Implemented a mock pipeline in a Linux shell to test various security products and the various pipeline systems
- Reported progress to the CTO

SOFT SKILLS & **ATTRIBUTES**

Leadership: strong people management skills and staff motivation/guidance.

Strong analytical, design and solution enthused problemsolving skills.

Deadline orientated, selfmotivated and energetic with a keen sense of urgency on set deliverables.



LANGUAGES

English (Home language)



🖄 HOBBIES

Airsoft, Motocross, Drumming and Video Games

Junior Software Engineer

Kindle Insurance Technologies, Johannesburg, South Africa, Jan 2023 – Current

Role: Software Engineer

- Developed solutions on the KIT system for clients which included working with multiple technologies. These tasks ranged from creating alterable and modifiable PDF/Excel documents creating new pages and functionalities.
- Acquired and used insurance concepts and terminology to communicate to clients and utilise with development tasks.
- Integrated new technologies into existing code.
- Performed testing on worked generated by the team and myself, to ensure there were no errors.
- Ensuring efficiency, adherence to best practices, and continuous improvement.
- Implement development methodologies, tools, and standards for the teams.
- Resolved coding errors.
- Developed, maintained, and implemented software within time constraints set by clients or goals.
- Partook in meetings that focus on delegation and distribution of work as well as brain storming problems and issues related to the company's software.
- Online support for clients
- Researching and implementing new technologies such as implementing new software for creating documents.
- Leasing with clients over requested tasks in an efficient and timely manner.
- Participated in training sessions subjected around insurance and the understanding of Kindle's software.
- Worked collaboratively in a team and contributed to the project success, focus being on multiple clients and their various requests.
- Stay up to date with the latest technologies, trends, and industry best practices.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Technology



Years Used

recimology	rears Oseu
Adobe XD	2
Agile Environment	2
AngularJS	4
ASP .NET	4
AWS Development	1
Azura DevOps	1
C#	4
C++	2
CSS	5
Figma	1
Flutter	1
GitHub	3
HTML	5
Java	2
JavaScript	4
JSON	3
LINQ	1
MongoDB	2
MySQL	3
Nodejs	3
Object Orientated Programming	6
PHP	2

Postgre-SQL	3
Python	2
ReactJS	3
REST API	3
TypeScript	4
Unity	1
XML Schema	2